### Contact

steph777@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/stephanierosser-dnp-aprn-37378b80 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Acute Care
Nursing
Nurse Practitioners

# Stephanie Rosser DNP, APRN

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner at Envision

Alvin, Texas

### Summary

Experienced Nurse Practitioner, Leader, & Educator, with a demonstrated history of achieving quality outcomes. Highly skilled in Leadership, Acute & Chronic Disease Management, Project Management, Quality Improvement, Care Transitions, and Nursing Education. Certifications include: AGACNP-C, CCRN-CMC, NEA-BC.

### Experience

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Assistant Professor

August 2012 - Present (7 years 10 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Nursing Faculty, Adult /Geriatric Acute Care Nurse Practitioner Program

#### **EmCare**

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner June 2016 - Present (4 years)

Houston, Texas Area

Hospitalist Service

#### SWR NP SERVICE

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner
October 2013 - Present (6 years 8 months)

CHI St. Luke's Health - Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center Nurse Practitioner- Medical Quality CV Service Line October 2017 - May 2018 (8 months)

Houston, Texas

HCA Bayshore Medical Center Stroke NP/Program Coordinator August 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 5 months) HCA-Bayshore Medical Center Acute Care Nurse Practitioner- Sepsis Initiative May 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Acute Care Nurse Practitioner, Sepsis Innovation Grant

Responsibilities include implementation and sustainment of the grant funded Sepsis Early Recognition and Response Initiative (SERRI) at the Bayshore Medical Center Campus. Provide education for sepsis primary and secondary responders. Function as the primary Second Level Responder for the Bayshore campus. Collaborate with medical staff to initiate Sepsis protocols when warranted with the aim of reducing the mortality of Sepsis in the hospitalized patient. Partner with the ICU director to identify ICU charge nurses capable of functioning as a second level responder and facilitate training in order to provide around the clock in house second level responder coverage. Partner with the director of education to coordinate sepsis related educational activities for staff. Participate in quality improvement relative to sepsis outcomes. Conduct clinical case reviews for patients diagnosed with Severe Sepsis and Septic Shock. Evaluate care delivery, patient outcomes, opportunities for improvement and report findings to the director of quality and the Chief Medical Officer. Collaborate with ICU director to identify and correct variances in nursing practice and assist with education relative to knowledge gaps. Provide sepsis education to nursing and medical staff on an ongoing basis. Partner with CNO to develop Advanced Practice Council.

Harris Health System 8 years 5 months

Director of Nursing, Cardiology Services June 2010 - March 2013 (2 years 10 months)

Ben Taub General Hospital

Responsibilities Include providing multi-department operational oversight including fiscal, human resource management, strategic planning, and quality of care provision for the Coronary Care Unit, Cardiac/Medical Surgical Intermediate Care Unit, Medical/Cardiac Observation Unit and Post Cardiac Procedure Unit.

#### **Key Achievements**

• Expansion of Cardiology Service Line through collaboration with nursing and physician partners

- Collaborated with the Chief of Cardiology and Ambulatory Chief Nursing Officer to develop a comprehensive approach for managing heart failure patients across the health care continuum using a disease management approach. This initiative reduced 30 day readmission rates for CHF.
- Re-opened two nursing units to serve adult medical patients and post cardiac procedure patients
- Achieved high levels of staff satisfaction as evidenced by highest pavilion scores measured via NDNQI nurse survey 2 years in a row.
- Collaborated with physician and nursing leaders to develop a cardiac catheterization lab cross training program for the CCU nurses. The outcome of this initiative is a sustained trend of exceeding national door to balloon times for AMI primary PCI.
- Developed a multi departmental strategic plan to maximize operations and achieve 2 year and 5 year outcome indicators in alignment with the department of nursing and district wide strategic plan.
- Participated in the development of the Nursing Clinical Advancement
   Program including development of new job descriptions and addendums with measurable performance indicators.
- Served on the Differentiated Practice Task Force.
- Participated in the development of new job descriptions and addendums of the cardiac monitor technicians with measurable performance indicators.
- Partnered with senior administration, physicians, nurse leaders, and biomed stakeholders to develop an operational plan for the expansion of telemetry services as a strategy to improve overall hospital throughput.

Clinical Nurse Liaison, Medical Surgical Services December 2009 - June 2010 (7 months)

Ben Taub General Hospital

Functioned in a supportive role to the Administrative Director of the Medical Surgical Service; Served as a consultant to unit level nursing leadership; Performed unit based assessments of nursing practice and overall quality of clinical care provision. Identified variance in nursing practice and developed action plans with measurable outcomes to improve nursing practice and patient care delivery. Conducted clinical case reviews and participated in root cause analysis for near miss events and sentinel events. Supported unit based leadership in implementing and evaluating corrective actions.

Nursing Clinical Educator Trauma and Critical Care Services August 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 5 months)

Ben Taub General Hospital

Functioned in a supportive role to the Administrative Director of the Trauma and Critical Care Service; Served as a consultant to unit level nursing leadership; Partnered with district nursing education to conduct needs assessments and plan educational activities. Co- Instructor for Houston Area Collaborative Critical Care Program Basic Dysrhythmia Course; Coordinated CCRN review courses to increase the number of certified critical care nurses within the service and achieved a 25% increase of certified nurses within the service; Collaborated with the HCHD foundation to write grant proposals for funding educational programs. Led nursing internship program for critical care nurse interns; facilitated evidence based practice projects on the nursing units. Identified variance in nursing practice and developed action plans with measurable outcomes to improve nursing practice and patient care delivery. Conducted clinical case reviews and participated in root cause analysis for near miss events and sentinel events. Supported unit based leadership in implementing and evaluating corrective actions.

Clinical Service Specialty Coordinator Cardiology Services
July 2007 - August 2008 (1 year 2 months)

Ben Taub General Hospital

Functioned in a supportive role to the nurse manager; provided educational activities within cardiology service. Collaborated with medical and nursing staff to develop service based policy and procedure. Supported medical staff and nurse manager in the opening of the cardiology specialty clinic and provided oversight for the day to day operations of the cardiology clinic.

Staff Nurse Cardiac Catheterization Lab April 2006 - July 2007 (1 year 4 months) Ben Taub General Hospital

Functioned as a staff nurse and charge nurse in the cardiac catheterization lab; partnered with the service chief and nurse manager on performance improvement initiatives. Collaborated with the service chief to develop order sets for pre/post procedure patients and developed standard discharge instructions for post procedure patients and revised pacemaker and AICD discharge instructions.

Staff Nurse Medical Intensive Care Unit November 2004 - April 2006 (1 year 6 months) Ben Taub General Hospital

Functioned as a staff nurse and charge nurse; Functioned as a preceptor for newly hired staff nurses and nurse interns.

## Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Doctor of Nursing Practice- DNP, Executive Leadership · (2014 - 2017)

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston Masters Degree, Nursing Science · (2009 - 2011)